字幕整理制作: jifanzimu@tutamail.com 欢迎交流
艾  琳
♪我的爱没有开始
♪ My love has no beginning ♪
♪我的爱没有尽头
♪ My love has no end ♪
♪没有前后  我的爱不会弯曲
♪ No front or back, and my love won't bend ♪
♪我在中间
♪ I'm in the middle ♪
♪迷失在旋转中
♪ Lost in a spin ♪
♪爱你...
♪ Loving you... ♪
♪你不知道
♪ And you don't know ♪
♪你不知道 你不知道 你不知道
♪ You don't know, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪我是多么高兴
♪ How glad I am ♪
♪我的爱没有底 我的爱没有顶
♪ My love has no bottom, my love has no top ♪
♪我的爱不会上升  我的爱不会下降
♪ My love won't rise, and my love won't drop ♪
♪我在中间
♪ I'm in the middle ♪
♪我无法停止
♪ And I can't stop ♪
♪爱你...
♪ Loving you... ♪
♪你不知道 你不知道 你不知道
♪ And you don't, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪你不知道我有多高兴
♪ You don't know how glad I am ♪
♪我希望我是一个诗人
♪ I wish I were a poet ♪
♪那样我可以表达
♪ So I could express ♪
♪我想
♪ What I'd ♪
♪我想说的是
♪ What I'd like to say, yeah ♪
♪我希望我是一个艺术家
♪ I wish I were an artist ♪
♪所以我可以画一幅画
♪ So I could paint a picture ♪
♪画出我的感受
♪ Of how I feel ♪
♪画出我今天的感受
♪ Of how I feel today, yeah ♪
♪我的爱没有墙壁的两侧
♪ My love has no walls on either side ♪
♪这让我的爱更加宽广
♪ That makes my love wider than wide ♪
♪我在中间
♪ I'm in the middle ♪
♪我隐藏不了
♪ And I can't hide ♪
♪爱你...
♪ Loving you... ♪
♪你不知道 你不知道 你不知道
♪ And you don't, you don't know, you don't know ♪
♪你不知道我有多高兴
♪ You don't know how glad I am ♪
♪我是多么高兴
♪ How glad I am ♪
♪我是多么高兴...
♪ How glad I am... ♪
艾琳
Eileen.
Eileen!
我需要 I-37 表格
I need form I-37.
- 转账表格？ - 不
- Transfer form? - No.
入口 I-37.
Intake. I-37.
你没在听吗
Aren't you listening?
她一无是处
She is useless.
弗莱博士还需要签字
Dr. Frye still needs to sign it.
他可能在办公室睡觉呢
He's probably asleep in his office.
哦 是的
Oh, yeah.
也许你可以去叫醒弗莱医生
Maybe you could go wake up Dr. Frye.
在他耳边轻轻吹气
Blow softly in his ear.
他喜欢这样
He loves that.
离艾琳远点
Leave Eileen alone.
她累了
She's tired.
哦 是这样吗
Oh, is that what it is?
我还以为是每月都来的那事呢
I thought maybe it was that time of the month.
至少我每个月都还来
At least I have a time of the month.
哦 你知道吗 亲爱的？
Oh, yeah. You know something, honey?
不会永远都来的 你很快就会像我们一样变老
It won't last forever. You'll be old like us soon.
纳尔逊夫人请到探视区
Mrs. Nelson to the visiting area, please.
纳尔逊夫人请到探访区
Mrs. Nelson to the visiting area.
我不会和任何人打架我告诉过你
I'm not gonna fight with anybody. I told you.
米奇怎么样了？
How's Mickey doing?
我在努力做好人
I'm trying to be good.
坐下 坐下坐下
Sit down. Sit down. Sit down.
好吧 这不是我的错...
Well, it's not my fault...
下次再见吧
Maybe I'll see you next time.
就像我们会想念那只老狗一样
As much as we're gonna miss the old dog,
希望你们都能欢迎
I hope you'll all be welcoming
弗莱博士的继任者
to Dr. Frye's replacement on Monday.
一位优秀的年轻医生
A fine, fine young doctor.
是啊 希望孩子们能好好对待她
Yes, well, let's hope the boys take her seriously.
我来对待她
I'll take her.
好好的
Seriously.
你好好的注射胰岛素
I think you will be taking your insulin
还有退休计划吧
and your retirement package.
这就够了
That'll be enough for you.
没错
That's right.
我会想念这里的快乐日子
I'll really miss all the fun around here.
让我们为弗莱博士鼓掌
Let's hear it for Dr. Frye.
干杯
Cheers!
我最近经常看到安妮
I see a lot of Anne these days.
是啊 很多人的心都碎了
Yeah, a lot of broken hearts out there.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, hon.
嘿
Hey.
你爸爸还好吗
How's your dad?
很好
Good.
你知道吗 让我来
You know what? Let me get that.
谢谢
Thanks.
想让你进去闭上你的臭嘴
Want you to go inside and shut the fuck up!
你闭嘴...你闭嘴！
You shut... you shut up!
- 滚开闭嘴！  - 你闭嘴
- Fuck off! Shut up! - You shut up!
- 该死的酒袋  - 哦 我会做...
- Fucking booze bag! - Oh, I'll do...
- 我要喝一杯  - 你没事吧 长官？
- I'm gonna have a drink. - You all right there, chief?
你可以滚蛋了
You can fuck right off.
问题出在隔壁该死的路德教徒身上 而不是我
Goddamn Lutherans next door are the problem, not me.
没有人抱怨 我们只是想确保
Nobody's complaining. We just want to make sure
你们会平安回家
you're getting home safe and sound.
没人抱怨吗
Nobody's complaining?
- 爸爸  - 安然无恙？
- Dad. - Safe and sound?
- 我为什么不能安然无恙？ - 爸爸
- Why wouldn't I be safe and sound? - Dad.
我让整个街区安然无恙
I keep the whole fucking neighborhood safe and sound.
- 你知道什么？ - 爸爸
- What do you know? - Dad.
艾琳 进去
E-Eileen, go inside.
- 好的爸爸 看我  - 进去吧
- Okay. Dad, look to me. - Go inside.
来吧求你了 求你了
Come on. Please. Please.
嘿 你惹麻烦了
Hey! You're causing a scene.
相信我 艾琳没人想和你在一起
Trust me, Eileen. Nobody wants nothing with you.
- 好的
- Okay. - Mwah!
- 进去吧  - 姆瓦
- Come on. Go inside. - Mwah!
该死的路德教徒
Goddamn Lutherans right there.
你妈妈一直很讨厌那些人
Your mother always hated those people.
- 天哪 我们进去吧  - 他们可以滚了当然可以
- Gosh, let's go inside. - They can fuck off. Sure.
你不能到处去管人 爸爸
You can't go around policing people, Dad.
谁说的？你知道那家伙是谁吗
Who says? You know who that guy was?
一切都在我们掌握之中 长官
We got it all under control, chief.
你可以放轻松请吧
You can take it easy. Please.
别紧张？你他妈的别激动
Take it easy? Y-You fuckin' take it easy.
你不再是警察了
You're not a cop anymore.
是的 当然
Yeah, sure.
我不想退休 他们逼我的
I didn't want to retire. They made me,
因为我太他妈擅长这个了
'cause I was too goddamn good at it.
听着 我得回局里去
Look, I gotta get back to the station.
给我倒杯酒好的
Pour me a drink. Good.
回局里去 巴克
Get back to the station, Buck.
把酒给我
Give me my drink.
如有需要 请给我们打电话
Just give us a call if you need anything.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
嘿 过来什么味道？
Hey, come here. What's that smell?
你踩到什么东西了吗
Did you step in something?
没有 怎么了？你闻到了什么？
No. Why? What do you smell?
我不知道 马路杀手
I don't know. Roadkill.
也许你应该保持距离
Maybe you should keep your distance.
我会保持距离的
Yeah, I'll keep my distance.
你他妈的在干什么？把我的鞋穿上
The fuck you doing? Put my fucking shoes back on.
但也许你应该对我好一点
But maybe you should be nicer to me.
没有人会忍受你的鬼话
No one else is gonna put up with your shit.
那就去吧 因为我抓到了琼妮
Go then, 'cause I got Joanie.
她可不会把房子收拾成这个样子
She wouldn't keep a place looking like this.
她是个真正的女人 你的姐姐
She's a real woman, your sister.
而且她闻起来像个女人
And she smells like a woman.
她知道如何打理家务！
She knows how to keep a house!
她不住在这里 而且已经结婚了！
And she doesn't live here, and she's married!
是啊 因为她不是吊丝
Yeah, 'cause she's not a hanger-on.
她不想跟你说话
And she doesn't want to talk to you!
是啊 当然 因为她有自己的生活
Yeah, sure, 'cause she's made a life of her own.
她已经有所成就
She's made something of herself.
随便吧 爸爸
Whatever, Dad.
过你自己的生活吧 艾琳 找点线索
Get a life, Eileen. Get a clue.
妈的
Shit.
去他妈的
Fuck it.
好了 听好了
All right, listen up!
众所周知 在新的一年里
As you know, in the new year,
我们将接受州审查
we will be up for state review.
因此 我们将收紧程序
So we're gonna be tightening our procedures
并根据一些重大的新想法实施新战略
and implementing new strategies based on some big, new ideas.
说到这 我左边这位新来的年轻女士
And on that note, this new young lady to my left,
瑞贝卡博士
Dr. Miss Rebecca St. John,
是我们新的监狱心理学家
is our new prison psychologist.
她刚刚完成了拉德克利夫大学的博士学位
She's just finished her doctorate at Radcliffe.
哈佛大学
Harvard.
啊 哈佛
Ah. Harvard.
我们可能不是哈佛人
We may not be Harvard people,
但我认为我们能跟上她
but I think we can keep up with her,
希望她能跟上我们的步伐
and hopefully she can keep up with us
因为我们跟上了他们的步伐
as we keep up with them.
她也许很平易近人 但我向你保证
She may be easy on the eyes, but I assure you,
她非常聪明
she is very smart.
女士们 我希望你们带圣约翰小姐四处转转...
Ladies, I hope you show Miss St. John around...
琉璃多少钱？
Say, how much for a glazed?
它们是免费的
They're free.
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
我是丽贝卡
I'm Rebecca.
我知道
I know.
我说 这附近哪里能让女孩梳洗打扮呢？
Say, where can a girl get freshened up around here?
我可以演示给你看
I can show you.
好的 谢谢
Sure. Appreciate it.
我能拿你的外套吗
Can I take your jacket?
你是不是很可爱？谢谢
Aren't you sweet? Thanks.
这样
This way.
我想我没听清你的名字
I don't think I caught your name.
艾琳
Eileen.
- 早安  - 早上好
- Morning. - Morning.
你从哪里来？
Where you from?
啊？
Huh?
我来自纽约
Oh, I'm from New York originally.
曼哈顿
Manhattan.
受不了剑桥 太紧张了
Couldn't stand Cambridge. Way too uptight.
有几个人很有意思
Well, there were a couple of interesting people,
但是 不 我需要休息一下
but, no, I needed a break.
呼吸新鲜空气
Get some fresh air.
我喜欢海滩
And I love the beach.
好的
All right.
32...
24...
34.
实际上是我的尺寸
Practically my measurements.
你知道 有些女性认为她们的身材
You know, some women think their figures
才是最重要的
are the only thing that matters.
说实话 我觉得这有点可悲
Honestly, I think that's kind of pathetic.
我完全同意
I completely agree.
我妹妹也是这样 而且她不太聪明
My sister's like that, and she's not very smart.
很好那你和我
Mm, good. Then you and I
有比我们的数字更值得讨论的事情
have better things to discuss than our figures.
尽管这并不是大众的观点
Although that isn't the popular opinion,
你说是不是？
wouldn't you say?
我不在乎流行什么
I don't care what's popular.
看看你
Well, look at you.
一个普通的凯瑟琳·赫本
A regular Katharine Hepburn.
如此有魄力的年轻女性实属罕见
Rare to meet a young woman with so much gumption.
我也是这样
I'm like that, too.
我才不管别人怎么想
I don't give a rat's ass what people think.
他们可能怕你
They're probably scared of you.
莫伊？
Moi?
好的 再见
All right. See you around.
每年
Every year, -
我们举行这次特别大会
we hold this special assembly
庆祝主耶稣基督的诞生
to celebrate the birth of Our Lord Jesus Christ.
每年 你们中都有一个变态混蛋
And every year, one of you sick bastards
毁了我们其他人
ruins it for the rest of us.
你最后一次不尊重圣诞节了
Well, you've disrespected Christmas for the last time
因为今年 你只能坐以待毙
because this year, you're gonna sit on your hands,
你要拉紧你的嘴唇
you're gonna zip your lips.
如果我看到你们有人咬人、踢人、尖叫、推人
If I see any of you biting, kicking, screaming, pushing,
扯头发、大笑、呻吟
pulling hair, laughing, moaning,
或者我听到一句不中听的话
or I hear one wayward comment,
你们直接去洞穴
you're going straight to the cave.
现在 话不多说
And now, without further ado,
我很荣幸地感谢奥利弗山的人们
it is my honor to thank the people from Mount Olive
今年再次帮助我指导盛会的人...
who helped me direct the pageant again this year...
- 耶 奥利弗山  - 向你们介绍
- Yay, Mount Olive. - And present to you
"狱中圣诞"
"Christmas in Prison."
我要在圣诞节杀人
I'm gonna kill someone on Christmas.
闭嘴
Shut up!
哦 我该怎么办？
Oh, what am I to do?
被判室内禁闭三年
Sentenced for three years to sit indoors
在与我信条相同的男孩中 这简直是糟糕透顶
among boys of my same creed, plain bad.
有这么多时间来策划
So much time to plot
我一出来就会做什么坏事
what evildoings I'll undertake as soon as I get out.
想吃蛋糕吗 胖子？
You want some cake, you fatty?!
同时 我想我可以读一本书
In the meantime, I suppose I could read a book.
你不识字 混蛋
You can't read, motherfucker!
该死的莎士比亚
Fucking Shakespeare up here.
我现在很潦倒
I'm scrappy right now.
真理之书
Book of truth!
哦 看看麦卡利斯特
Oh, look at McAllister.
该死的麦卡利斯特
Fucking McAllister.
嘿 架子不错！
Hey, nice rack!
我很累了
Well, I'm-I'm pretty tired.
我们能在那边的谷仓里休息吗
Can we rest in that barn over there?
总比住汽车旅馆强
Better than paying for a motel.
你是最棒的 约瑟夫
You're the best, Joseph.
感谢您带我们来这里参加人口普查
Thank you for taking us here to be counted in the census.
去他妈的
Fuck this shit!
- 警卫  - 等等
- Guard! - Wait.
- 等等 等等等等 等等  - 嘿 抓住他
- Wait. Wait, wait. - Hey, grab him.
后退
Move back!
你们都坐下
All you guys sit down!
给我坐下
Sit the fuck down!
嘿 鲍勃
Hey, Bob.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey, hon.
这个和一包幸运糖
This and a pack of Luckies.
今天真幸运 是吧？
Oh! It's a lucky day, huh?
是啊 最幸运的
Yeah, the luckiest.
是的 香烟很不错
Yup. Cigarettes are great.
不要引火烧身
Don't light yourself on fire.
你心情这么好 怎么了？
You're in a good mood, what's wrong with you?
没事 爸爸
Nothing's wrong, Dad.
你嘴里含着那个东西 看起来很滑稽
You look funny with that thing in your mouth.
今天过得怎么样 爸爸？
How was your day, Dad?
我今天过得怎么样？
How was my day?
我不知道
I don't know.
这是一天 又是一天
It was a day, just another day.
有什么意义？
What's the point?
我今天过得很糟糕
My day was a doozy.
哦 是吗
Oh, yeah?
圣诞庆典上发生了一场大战
A big fight broke out at the Christmas pageant.
孩子的锁骨断了
Kid got his collarbone broken,
我不得不为典狱长做这些文书工作
and I had to do all this paperwork for the warden.
不要在地板上撒灰 那很俗气
Don't ash on the floor, it's tacky.
总之...
Anyway...
这是让人终生难忘的一天
It was one of those days you never forget.
哦 是吗 我永远不会忘记的日子
Oh, yeah? Days I'll never forget.
让我看看
Let me see.
1944 年 12 月 16 日
December 16, 1944,
这是我第一次把死人的头抱在腿上
first time I ever held a dead man's head in my lap.
真是浪费
What a waste.
室外气温 20 度 正在下雪
20 degrees outside and snowing.
就像这里一样
Just like it is here.
我都不知道自己为什么会回到这个地方
Don't know why I ever came back to this place.
也许是因为你有妻子和两个孩子
Maybe because you had a wife and two kids.
也许吧
Maybe.
我爱海滩
I love the beach.
哦 是吗 对你有好处
Oh, yeah? Good for you.
战争毁了我的海滩
War kind of ruined beaches for me.
还有什么？
So what else?
那个叫波尔克的孩子怎么样了？他说话了吗
How's that Polk kid? He talked yet?
啊？
Huh?
波尔克
Polk.
刺伤父亲的孩子...
The kid who stabbed his father...
他或多或少是个好警察
who was a good cop, more or less.
什么样的孩子会想到这样杀死自己的父亲？
What kind of kid thinks of killing his father like that?
在他睡觉时捅他一刀...
Stab him in his sleep...
在他母亲面前
in front of his mother.
然后他就坐下了
Then he just sits down.
从不否认
Never denies it.
在整个审判过程中一言不发
Never says a word the whole trial.
心理变态
Psychopathic.
我当然不用担心你
Course I wouldn't have to worry about you
做这样的事情 现在 我会吗
doing something like that, now, would I?
因为你是个女孩
'Cause you're a girl.
无法想象你拿着刀的样子
Can't imagine you with a knife.
你能想象我拿着枪的样子吗
Can you imagine me with a gun?
是的 我看得出来
Yeah, I can see it.
有一天...
One day...
当你受够了 觉得...
when you've had enough and you feel like, uh...
躲开
ducking out.
也许等我死后
Maybe when I'm dead and gone
你谁也没有 永远也不会有
and you got nobody and you never will.
我能想象得到
I could imagine that.
但你不会 对吧？
But you wouldn't, would you?
因为你太厉害了
'Cause you're too good.
说 给我一支烟
Say, give me one of those cigarettes.
你有什么 老金？
What have you got, Old Gold?
不
No.
我喜欢老金
I like Old Gold.
我知道
I know.
哎呀
Oopsie.
需要帮助吗
Do you need any help?
不 我没事
Uh, no, I'm okay.
就是黄油手指
Just butterfingers.
你应该看看我
You should see me.
我笨手笨脚的
I'm a total klutz.
哦 对了
Oh, right.
李·波尔克
Lee Polk.
这可不是每天都能看到的
That's not something you see every day.
是的 很糟糕
Yeah, it's pretty bad.
睡前阅读？
Bedtime reading?
我只是在整理文件
I was just doing some filing.
昨天的表演真精彩
That's some show yesterday.
他们每年都这样做
They do it every year.
我认为这是残忍和不寻常的惩罚
I'd call that cruel and unusual punishment.
对不起我通常不抽烟
Sorry. I don't usually smoke.
这是一个令人讨厌的习惯
It's a nasty habit.
这就是我喜欢它的原因
That's why I like it.
不过 这可不像一位淑女
Not very becoming of a lady, though.
使牙齿变黄
Turns your teeth yellow.
看到了吗
See?
那就是香烟和咖啡
That's cigarettes and coffee.
还有红酒
And red wine.
不 你的牙齿很完美
No, your teeth are perfect.
我不喝咖啡
I don't drink coffee,
所以我的牙齿应该没问题 但是...
so my teeth should be fine, but...
都烂了
they're all rotted
因为我特别爱吃甜食
due to my extreme propensity for sweets.
喜欢甜食
A propensity for sweets.
你的生活还不够甜蜜吗
You don't get enough sweetness in your life?
我只是吃了很多糖果
I just eat a lot of candy.
嗯 看着你我都不知道
Mm. I wouldn't know it to look at you.
你真娇小
You're so petite.
当然 个子高也有个子高的好处
Being tall has its advantages, of course,
但对我来说 大多数男人都太矮了
but most men are just too short for me.
你注意到了吗 还是我在胡思乱想？
Have you noticed, or am I imagining things,
现在的男人越来越矮
that men these days are getting shorter and shorter,
更秃 更胖？
balder, and fatter?
这里所有的男人都是小男孩
All the men around here are little boys.
你真有趣
You're funny.
我是说在监狱外面
I meant outside this prison.
虽然你说得对
Although you're right.
守卫 典狱长
The guards, the warden,
它们没什么好看的
they're not much to look at.
你应该去看弗莱医生的
You should have seen Dr. Frye.
他长得真的很猥琐
He was really pretty nasty looking.
我对此并不感到惊讶
That doesn't surprise me.
我的办公室并不宽敞
My office isn't very becoming,
而这一切都散发着肮脏皮革的味道
and it all smells of dirty leather.
我开始怀疑里面到底发生了什么
I'm beginning to wonder what went on in there.
没什么好东西
Nothing good.
我是说 我从未真正进过那间办公室
I mean, I never actually been in that office.
哦 你有空应该过来看看
Oh. Well, you should come by sometime.
虽然门是关着的
Although if the door's closed,
这意味着我和其中一个男孩在一起
that means I'm with one of the boys.
好的
Okay.
你难道不害怕吗
Aren't you ever scared
一个人和他们在一起？
being alone in there with them?
不
No.
有空来找我 好吗
Come by, and see me sometime, all right?
不过 如果你听到我在里面尖叫的话
Although, you know, if you hear me screaming in there,
请随时踢门救我
feel free to kick down the door and rescue me.
好的
Okay.
我开玩笑的 亲爱的
I'm just kidding, honey.
有蜂鸣器
There's a buzzer.
我是来见伦纳德·波尔克的
I'm here to see Leonard Polk.
安妮·波尔克
Anne Polk.
你不在日程表上
You're not on the schedule.
你是后来加入的吗
Are you a late addition?
我是被叫来的
I-I was called.
我不知道 我现在就在这里
I don't know, I-I'm here now.
你需要填写一份表格
Well, you need to fill out a form.
你不是邓洛普酋长的孩子吗
Aren't you Chief Dunlop's kid?
是啊
Yeah.
我想也是
I thought so.
波尔克夫人？我是圣约翰医生
Mrs. Polk? I'm Dr. St. John.
我们通过电话 非常感谢你能来
We spoke on the phone. Thank you so much for coming.
哦 没必要这么麻烦
Oh, no need to bother with that.
我们都知道你是谁
We all know who you are.
艾琳 你能帮我们开门吗
Eileen, would you help us with the door?
谢谢
Thank you.
是这样的
It's this way.
拿上你的外套？
Take your coat?
请
Please.
谢谢你 艾琳
Thank you, Eileen.
你先请
After you.
你为什么要这样对我？
Why are you doing this to me?
啊？
Huh?
你有话要说吗
You got something to say to me?
让我出去
Let me out!
让我出去让我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
让我出去
Let me out!
你们...你们想怎么处置他就怎么处置他
Y-You do... y'all do what you want with him.
甚至不愿意和自己的母亲说话？
Won't even talk to his own mother?
他一直是个讨厌的孩子
He's always been a nasty boy.
一个肮脏下流的男孩
A filthy, nasty boy!
我需要锁门
I need to lock up.
实际上 探视时间在 20 分钟前就已经结束了
Visitation hours were actually over 20 minutes ago.
哦 我明白了
Oh, I-I understand.
你想在我的办公室里继续说话吗
Would you like to keep talking in my office?
- 我们走  - 转过去
- Let's go. - Turn around.
哦 不用了没这个必要
Oh, no. That won't be necessary.
- 我得把他铐起来  - 不
- I need to cuff him. - No.
别担心 李没事的
Don't worry, Lee. It's all right.
没有这个必要
That won't be necessary.
别这样她是个医生
Don't do that. She's a doctor.
我觉得她需要看医生
I think she needs a doctor.
那孩子杀了个警察
That kid killed a cop.
他杀死了自己的父亲
He killed his father.
这两者是有区别的
There's a difference.
哦 真对不起让我看看是谁
Oh, I'm so sorry. Let me see who it is.
哦 艾琳
Oh, Eileen.
有什么能帮您的吗
Um, can I help you?
你忘带笔记本了
You forgot your notebook.
哦 太谢谢你了
Oh, thank you so much.
我真的需要这个
I actually need this.
嗯 希望你没读过
Um, hope you didn't read it.
- 不 当然不是  - 当然没有
- No, of course not. - Oh, no,
我开玩笑的 只是鸡爪而已
I'm just kidding. It's just chicken scratch.
等等 艾琳
Wait. Eileen.
我并不是想咄咄逼人
I don't mean to be forward,
而且 嗯 你可能已经有其他计划了
and, um, you probably have other plans already,
不过 今晚我能请你喝一杯吗
but, um, can I take you to a drink tonight?
我在这个该死的镇子里一个人都不认识
I don't know anyone in this darn town,
如果你愿意 我很乐意请你喝鸡尾酒
and I'd love to treat you to a cocktail if you're game.
- 好的
- Okay. - Okay?
我拧了你的胳膊？
I've twisted your arm?
那么 谁调制的马提尼最好喝？
So, uh, who makes the best martini in town?
- 也许是奥哈拉餐厅？
- Maybe O'Hara's? - O'Hara's.
实际上 这是镇上唯一的一家酒吧
It's actually the only bar in town.
不 奥哈拉餐厅很不错
No, O'Hara's is good.
7 点见？
See you at 7:00?
带着铃铛？是这个意思吗
With bells on? Is that the expression?
♪我知道你受伤了
♪ I know you've been hurt ♪
啊！
Ah!
♪被其他某个人
♪ By someone else ♪
♪我可以告诉的方式
♪ I can tell by the way ♪
♪你带着自己
♪ You carry yourself ♪
♪但如果你让我
♪ But if you let me ♪
♪我会这么做
♪ Here's what I'll do ♪
♪我会照顾你
♪ I'll take care of you ♪
♪我爱过 失去过
♪ I... I've loved and lost ♪
♪和你一样
♪ The same as you ♪
♪所以你看 我知道
♪ So you see, I know ♪
♪就是你所经历的
♪ Just what you've been through ♪
♪但如果你让我
♪ But if you'll let me ♪
♪我会这么做
♪ Here's what I'll do ♪
♪哦 我必须照顾你
♪ Oh, I just got to take care of you ♪
♪你不必担心
♪ You won't ever have to worry ♪
♪你永远不会哭泣
♪ You won't ever have to cry ♪
♪因为我会在你身边
♪ For I'll be there beside you ♪
♪擦干你哭泣的双眼
♪ To dry your weeping eyes ♪
♪所以 亲爱的
♪ So, darling ♪
♪告诉我
♪ Tell me ♪
♪你会是真实的
♪ That you'll be true ♪
♪因为毫无疑问...
♪ For there is no doubt... ♪
- 艾琳
- Hi. - Oh, Eileen.
你好
Hi.
请坐下
Please, please, please, sit.
你要吃什么？
Um, what are you having?
呃 我想我还是喝啤酒吧
Uh, I'll have a beer, I guess.
啤酒？哦
A beer? Oh.
嗨 艾琳
Hi, Eileen.
很高兴见到你 亲爱的
Good to see you, hon.
接下来呢 亲爱的？
What's next, sweetheart?
嗯...我的天啊
Um, well... Oh, my stars.
你绝对冻僵了
You're absolutely frozen.
请给我一杯啤酒 也许再来点威士忌
Um, one beer, please, and maybe a little whiskey
来温暖我的女孩怎么样？
to warm up my girl. What say, huh?
天哪 你看起来真迷人
My, you look very glamorous.
这只是一件旧衣服
It's just an old dress.
可以吗
May I?
你呢 亲爱的？再来杯马提尼？
How about you, sweetheart? Another martini?
爱一个谢谢
Love one. Thank you.
也许这次我们先不要吃橄榄
Maybe let's hold the olives this time.
我以为我很难找到这个地方
I thought I'd have a hard time finding this place,
但还是来了
but here it is.
你还好吗
You feeling all right?
我没事
Yeah, I'm fine.
我的车有点问题
Uh, there's something wrong with my car,
所以我必须关着车窗开车
so I have to drive with the windows down,
否则就会烟雾弥漫
or else it fills with smoke.
哦 你在开玩笑
Oh, you're kidding.
这听起来太可怕了
That sounds absolutely awful.
你就不能让你丈夫帮你修好吗
Can't you get your husband to fix that for you?
哦 不 我还没结婚
Oh, no, I'm not married.
我一直都是单身
I've always been single.
当我身边有男人的时候
And when I do have a guy around,
只是为了好玩 而且时间很短
it's just for fun, and it's brief.
不 我从不在任何地方久留
No, I never stay anywhere long with anything.
我的生活方式
Sort of my modus vivendi
或我的病态 这取决于我在跟谁说话
or my pathology, depending on who I'm talking to.
您在摩尔黑德工作多久了？
How long have you worked at Moorehead?
三四年
Three or four years.
呃 本来只是暂时的
Uh, it was only supposed to be temporary,
母亲生病期间 我搬回来住了一段时间
while I moved back for a bit while my mother was sick,
然后她死了 所以
and then she died, so...
我一直在监狱里 时间过得飞快
I've been at the prison, and time's just flown by.
哦 上帝啊
Oh, God.
监狱不是时光飞逝的地方
Prison is no place for time to fly by.
还有你母亲的死
And your mother dying.
对一位年轻女士来说 这已经够多了
That's a lot for a young lady.
啊 24.
Ah. 24.
那你一定很想再出去走走 是吗
Then you must be eager to get back out there. Are you?
你知道 嗯 我也是个孤儿
You know, um, I'm an orphan, too.
我叔叔在西部把我抚养长大
My uncle raised me out West.
阳光普照的地方
Where the sun shines.
我不明白你们是怎么做到的
I don't understand how you all do it here,
一个冬天又一个冬天
winter after winter.
真让人毛骨悚然我也不知道
It's positively creepy. I don't know.
我对新英格兰有着一种奇怪的情结
I'm in a sort of strange love affair with New England.
我喜欢它 但也讨厌它
I love it, but I also hate it.
这里的一切都很真实 不是吗
Things feel very real here, don't they?
算是没有...
Sort of there's no...
想象力
imagination.
没有感伤 也没有幻想
There's no sentimentality or fantasy.
这里...这里无处可藏
There's... there's just nowhere to hide.
对不起
Sorry.
我喝多了
I've had too much to drink.
我一喝多就爱说话
I tend to talk when I've had too much to drink.
没事的
It's all right.
嗯 总比说得太少要好
Mm, it's better than talking too little.
你今天看到李·波尔克了吗
Did you see Lee Polk today?
呃...
Uh...
她跟你说什么了吗
Did she say anything to you?
波尔克夫人？
Mrs. Polk?
她只是心烦意乱
She was just upset.
那些母亲总是不高兴
Those mothers are always upset.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
你觉得她是个愤怒的女人吗
Did she seem like an angry woman to you?
我不知道呃...
I don't know. Uh...
大家都很生气
everyone's kind of angry here.
- 是马萨诸塞州  - 是马萨诸塞州
- It's Massachusetts. - Mm.
我在哈佛有一位教授
Well, I had this professor at Harvard.
他才华横溢 但非常棘手
He was brilliant, but very difficult.
呃 他在囚犯身上做了这些...这些实验
Uh, he did this... these experiments on prisoners
研究迷幻药对累犯的影响
studying the effects of psychedelics on recidivism.
现在 我不同意他的方法
Now, I don't agree with his methods,
世上没有灵丹妙药
there is no magic pill,
但是...但是你可以让人们自由...
but... but you can set people free...
如果你能让他们说出真相 感受到真相
if you can get them to tell the truth, to feel it.
这就是我想做的
That's what I want to do.
秘密与谎言
Secrets and lies.
我告诉你 娃娃...
I tell you, doll...
有些家庭太变态了 太扭曲了
some families are so sick, so twisted,
唯一的出路就是有人死掉
the only way out's for someone to die.
你觉得呢？
Don't you think?
你说你叫什么名字？
Hey! What'd you say your name was?
谁？
Who, me?
是啊我们刚才说
Ah, yeah. W-We was just saying
你看起来如此熟悉
that you look so familiar.
你是在拍电影吗
Are you in the movies or something?
很难说我在男子监狱工作
Hardly. I work at the boys' prison.
- 我是艾琳
- Ah. - I'm Eileen,
这是我的朋友丽贝卡
and this is my friend, Rebecca.
她是个心理学家
She's a psychologist.
别害羞 丽贝卡
Don't be shy, Rebecca.
这些孩子不会咬人
These boys won't bite.
除非你要求我们这样做
Not unless you ask us to.
这是杰瑞你可以无视他
This is Jerry. You can ignore him.
他结婚了
He's married.
你的牙齿怎么了 杰瑞？
What happened to your teeth, Jerry?
你和你老婆吵架了？
You get into a fight with your old lady?
就是这样他妻子的左手和乔·弗雷泽一样长
That's it. His wife's got a left like Joe Frazier.
不 不他...他在冰上滑倒了
Nah, nah. He... he slipped on the ice.
不过 我会再种一些新的
I'm gonna grow some new ones, though.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
只需要再多几个这样的东西
Just need a few more of these.
为此干杯为杰瑞和他的新牙干杯
Cheers to that. To Jerry and his new teeth.
嘿
Hey.
♪你一定非常想要
♪ You've gotta want it bad ♪
♪如果那家伙的得到 进入你的血液
♪ If that guy's got into your blood ♪
想跳舞吗 丽贝卡？
Feel like dancing, Rebecca?
和你？
With you?
是啊
Yeah.
♪你的心
♪ The very heart of you ♪
♪让你想呼吸
♪ Makes you want to breathe ♪
♪这里的事情要做
♪ Here's the thing to do ♪
♪告诉他你永远不会离开他
♪ Tell him that you're never gonna leave him ♪
♪告诉他你永远爱他
♪ Tell him that you're always gonna love him ♪
♪告诉他 现在就告诉他
♪ Tell him, tell him, tell him, tell him right now ♪
♪我知道一些关于爱
♪ I know something about love ♪
♪你得表示出来
♪ You gotta show it and ♪
♪让他看到天上的月亮
♪ Make him see the moon up above ♪
♪得到他
- ♪ Out and get him ♪ - ♪ Do, do-do ♪
♪如果你想让他永远在你身边
♪ If you want him to be always by your side ♪
♪如果你想让他只想着你
♪ If you want him to only think of you ♪
♪告诉他你永远不会离开他
♪ Tell him that you're never gonna leave him ♪
♪告诉他你永远爱他
♪ Tell him that you're always gonna love him ♪
♪告诉他 现在就告诉他
♪ Tell him, tell him, tell him, tell him right now ♪
♪从创世之初
♪ Ever since the world began ♪
♪男人和女人
♪ It's been that way for man ♪
♪就是这样
♪ And women... ♪
♪你嘴唇的触摸
♪ The touch of your lips ♪
♪在我旁边
♪ Next to mine ♪
♪让我兴奋
♪ Gets me excited ♪
♪- 让我感觉很好 - 不
- ♪ Makes me feel fine ♪ - No.
♪你的手的触摸
♪ The touch of your hand ♪
♪你甜蜜的问候
♪ Your sweet hello ♪
♪你内心的火热
♪ The fire inside you ♪
♪当你靠近我
♪ When you're holding me close ♪
♪你的爱如此温暖
♪ Your love so warm and tender ♪
♪哦 惊险刺激如此神圣
- ♪ Oh ♪ - ♪ The thrill is so divine ♪
♪总是这些
♪ It is all these things ♪
♪让你是我的
♪ That make you mine ♪
♪如果你离开
♪ If you would leave ♪
♪我肯定会死
♪ I surely would die ♪
♪当你迟到十分钟
♪ When you were ten minutes late ♪
♪我开始哭泣
♪ I started to cry ♪
♪啊 啊 啊
♪ Ah, ah, ah ♪
♪我已经得到了它坏
♪ I've got it bad ♪
♪可那也没事
♪ But it's all right ♪
♪只要你在这里
♪ As long as you're here ♪
♪每天晚上...
♪ Every night... ♪
你让我想起了荷兰油画中的一个女孩
You remind me of a girl in a Dutch painting.
你有一张奇怪的脸
You have a strange face.
它很普通 但...
It's plain, but...
迷人
fascinating.
它有一个美丽的...
It has a beautiful...
湍流
turbulence.
我喜欢
I love it.
我敢打赌 你的梦想一定很美好
I bet you have brilliant dreams.
我敢打赌 你一定梦见过其他世界
I bet you dream of other worlds.
也许你会梦见我和我清晨的懊悔
Maybe you'll dream of me and my morning remorse,
这是肯定的
which is certain.
我不该喝酒
I shouldn't drink,
但我愿意
but I do.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿 桑迪 能给我一杯马提尼酒和火柴吗
Hey, Sandy, can I get a martini and some matches?
最好小心点 艾琳
Better be careful, Eileen.
我不想跟你爸爸有任何瓜葛
I don't want any trouble with your dad.
我爸爸不会惹麻烦的
My dad's not gonna cause any trouble.
爸爸爸爸
Dad. Dad.
爸爸 能让我进去吗
Dad, can you let me in?
妈的
Shit.
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad!
能把钥匙给我吗
Can I have the keys?
Can I please have the keys?
不 你可能没有钥匙
No, you may not have the keys.
除非你从头到尾读完这本书
Not until you read that book from cover to cover.
我想听到每一个字
I want to hear every word.
你把钥匙放哪儿了？
Where'd you put the keys?
请随意 艾琳
Make yourself comfortable, Eileen.
在读完最后一个字之前 你哪儿也别想去
You're not going anywhere till you read the last word.
爸爸 这太荒唐了我得去上班了
Dad, this is ridiculous. I need to go to work.
整夜不归
Out all night.
差点撞车
Nearly crashed the car.
睡在自己的病床上
Sleeping in your own sick,
现在你又在担心能否准时上班？
and now you're worried about getting to work on time?
我几乎不敢看你 我太惭愧了
I can hardly look at you, I'm so ashamed.
奥利弗·忒斯特会对这个家感激不尽
Oliver Twist would be grateful for this home,
但是你 艾琳
but you, Eileen,
你是垃圾 艾琳 就是垃圾
you're trash, Eileen, just trash.
我所做的就是和一个女同事约会
All I did was go out with a girl from work.
你和一个女同事约会了？
You went out with a girl from work?
我看起来像昨天才出生的吗
Do I look like I was born yesterday?
他是谁？他是谁？
Who is he? Huh?
这个男孩是谁？我只想知道他是谁
Who is this boy? I just want to know who he is
在你怀孕并把灵魂出卖给撒旦之前
before you get knocked up and sell your soul to Satan.
你能把钥匙给我吗
Can you just give me the keys?!
求你了我要迟到了
Please! I'll be late!
你穿成这样哪儿也去不了
You're not going anywhere dressed like that.
我是说 真的 艾琳 你怎么敢？
I mean, really, Eileen, how dare you?
那是你母亲在我父亲葬礼上穿的衣服
That's the dress your mother wore to my father's funeral.
你不尊重任何人
You got no respect for anyone.
换衣服
Get changed.
我不想让任何人看到你穿成这样
I don't want anyone seeing you in that getup.
他们会以为我死了
They'll think I'm dead.
邓洛普小姐？邓洛普小姐？
Ah. Miss Dunlop?
我能说句话吗
May I, um, may I have a word?
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
是关于你父亲的
It's about your father.
他？去和他谈谈他在里面
Him? Go talk to him. He's inside.
是关于他的枪
It's about his gun.
这应该不错
This oughta be good.
请告诉我 巴克
Pray tell, Buck.
呃 昨天
Uh, yesterday,
我们收到了几位邻居的投诉
we got several complaints from neighbors,
学校的康妮小姐寄来的
from Miss Connie down at the school,
邓洛普局长
that, uh, Chief Dunlop
坐在朝北的窗前
was sitting in that north-facing window
并用武器指着他
and, uh, pointing his weapon
孩子们放学回家的路上
at children walking home from school.
他已同意将财产交由您照管
He has agreed to relinquish the property into your care.
只要你保证不把它用在他身上
As long as you promise not to use it on him.
他的话
His words.
我可以进来吗
May I come in?
想把它像装饰品一样挂在我身上吗
Want to hang it on me like an ornament?
胡
Aw.
我相信邓洛普小姐
I'm sure that Miss Dunlop
会好好保管武器的 长官
will take excellent care of the weapon, sir.
正如她对所有事情的态度一样 巴克 你也看到了
As she does with all things, Buck, as you can see.
♪圣诞时节
♪ It's Christmastime ♪
♪我想见圣诞老人
♪ And I wanna see Santa Claus ♪
♪什么？什么？
♪ What? What? What? ♪
♪是的 这是圣诞节
♪ Yes, it's Christmastime ♪
♪我想见圣诞老人
♪ And I wanna see Santa Claus ♪
♪什么？什么？
♪ What? What? What? ♪
♪会问他我的宝贝
♪ Gonna ask him for my baby ♪
♪这不是一个真正的好理由？
♪ Ain't that a real good cause? ♪
让我知道是哪些
Let me know which ones.
好的 我等着
Sure. I'll hold.
啊 看那只猫叼来了什么？
Ah, look what the cat dragged in.
下午好 艾琳
Good afternoon, Eileen.
你看起来像雏菊一样鲜艳 一如既往
You look fresh as a daisy, as always.
我的车出了问题
I had car trouble.
是的 我相信麻烦的部分
Yeah, I believe the trouble part.
快到圣诞节了 你能让我休息一下吗
It's almost Christmas. Can you give me a break?
不 去工作
No. Get to work.
好的 我需要波尔克的文件
Okay. I need the Polk file.
是啊
Yeah.
我想是圣约翰博士干的
I think Dr. St. John has it.
好极了是的 恐怕那个
Perfect. Yeah, I'm afraid that one
只能等到假期结束后了
will have to wait till after the holidays.
我们新来了一位医生
We have a new doctor on staff,
显然她不遵守程序
and, uh, apparently she doesn't follow procedures.
- 她今天没来？ - 已经走了
- She's not in today? - Been and gone.
她圣诞节后就会回来
She's gonna be back after Christmas.
好的好的
Yeah. Will do.
那好吧谢谢
All right, then. Thank you.
再见
Bye-bye.
你想去哪儿？
Where do you think you're going?
医务室
The infirmary.
我觉得周围有什么东西在流动
I think something's going around.
你看起来好像到处跑
You look like you've been going around.
她是个酒鬼
She's a boozer.
爸爸？
Dad?
爸爸 你能听到我吗
Dad, can you hear me?
- 你在上面干什么？ - 我需要我的枪
- What were you doing up there? - I need my gun.
- 坐起来  - 它在追我
- Sit up. - It's after me.
没人追杀你
Nobody's after you.
坐起来坐起来
Sit up. Sit up.
琼妮
Joanie.
是你吗 琼妮？
That you, Joanie?
嘿
Hey.
琼妮琼妮
Joanie. Joanie.
琼妮
Joanie.
爸爸
Dad.
别大惊小怪的 琼妮
Quit your fussing, Joanie.
我们给他缝合了伤口
We stitched him up,
我不认为他有脑震荡
and I don't think he has a concussion,
但他血液中的酒精含量
but his blood alcohol level
是 1·7 点
is point one-seven.
他的肝脏肿大 浑身是伤
His liver's enlarged, and he's covered in bruises.
我不是责怪你 亲爱的 但是...
I'm not blaming you, honey, but, uh...
是的 当然
Yeah, sure.
嘿 是谁让他这样生活的？
Hey, who's letting him live like this?
我不知道我妈妈去世了 他也没有工作
I don't know. My mom died, and he doesn't have a job.
他还能做什么？
What else is he supposed to do?
是的 有些男人不会整天喝酒
Yeah, there are men who don't drink all day.
我知道
I know that.
听着 我知道这对你来说很难 但是...
Look, I know this is hard for you, but, uh...
如果他不喝酒 他可能会死
if he stops drinking, he might die,
但如果他继续酗酒 肯定会要了他的命
but if he keeps drinking, it'll definitely kill him.
我不知道还能对你说什么
I don't know what else to say to you.
坐下 爸爸
Sit down, Dad.
医生说你快死了
The doctor told me you're gonna die.
哦 好像他没有？
Oh, like he's not?
他说 如果你继续这样喝下去
He said, if you keep drinking like this,
它会杀了你
it'll kill you.
去他的
Screw him.
你知道他们在那家医院杀了你母亲
You know they killed your mother at that hospital.
他们欠我的不只是缝针
They owe me more than stitches.
你能往后靠吗
Can you lean back?
我当然可以往后靠
Course I can lean back.
你以为我不知道怎么上床睡觉吗
You don't think I know how to go to bed?
我要喝一杯
Well, I need a drink.
爸爸
Dad!
总之 我不在这里睡觉
And anyway, I do not sleep here.
- 闹鬼了  - 求你了 爸爸
- It's haunted. - Please, Dad.
如果我给你拿个瓶子 你会躺下吗
If I get you a bottle, will you lie down?
不 我想和我女儿喝一杯
No. I want to have a drink with my daughter.
你现在不一样了
You're different these days.
你几乎很有趣
You're almost interesting.
你用工作赚来的钱做了什么？
What are you doing with all the money you make at work?
你为什么不买自己的衣服？
Why don't you ever buy your own clothes?
我记得那件大衣
I remember that coat.
我记得你的母亲...
I remember your mother...
我穿起来怎么样？
How does it look on me?
你妈妈穿那件大衣真漂亮
Well, your mother looked beautiful in that coat.
我买给她穿的
I bought it for her to wear
当她走出船舱时
when she got out of the bughouse.
我一直很爱你的母亲
I always loved your mother.
不管你觉得它看起来像什么
No matter what you thought it looked like,
我一直很爱她
I always loved her.
我知道人们是怎么说我的
And I know what people say about me.
他们说是我把她逼疯的 因为我是个硬骨头
They say I made her crazy 'cause I'm a hard-ass.
我可能还大喊了几声
And I may have yelled a few times,
但她总是原谅我
but she always forgave me.
因为我们彼此相爱
Because we loved each other.
爱会让你疯狂 艾琳
Love will make you crazy, Eileen.
你可能永远都不会明白
You'll probably never understand that.
为什么？
Why?
有些人...
Some people...
他们才是真正的人
they're the real people.
就像电影一样 你看的就是他们
Like in a movie, they're the ones you're watching.
是他们在行动
They're the ones making moves.
而其他人...
And the other people...
它们只是在那里填充空间
they're just there filling the space,
而你却认为这是理所当然的
and you take 'em for granted.
你觉得 "他们很容易"
You think, "They're easy."
拿一分钱 留一分钱
Take a penny, leave a penny.
这就是你 艾琳
That's you, Eileen.
你就是其中之一
You're one of them.
你在干什么？你不用锁门
What are you doing? You don't gotta lock it.
我们走吧
Let's go.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
来吧外面很冷
Come on. It's cold out here.
快点快点
Come on. Hurry up.
开门
Open the door.
真他妈重
Fucking heavy.
把他妈的酒给我
Give me my fucking drink.
艾琳
Eileen!
什么 爸爸？
What, Dad?
电话响了
Phone rang.
有个女人在找你
Some woman looking for you.
你说什么？
What'd you say?
什么都没有
Nothing.
我什么都不知道 我什么也没说
I know nothing. I said nothing.
你好
Hello.
你好 圣诞天使
Hello, Christmas angel.
丽贝卡？
Rebecca?
听着 我只是在想你
Look, I was just thinking of you,
我不知道
and, well, I-I don't know
平安夜有什么计划
what you're planning for Christmas Eve,
但我想也许你愿意过来
but I thought maybe you'd like to come over.
我们可以播放一些唱片
There are some records we could play,
如果一切顺利 也许还能再跳一次舞
and maybe dance again if all goes well.
当然 除非你有更好的提议
Unless you have a better offer, of course.
我没有更好的提议
I don't have a better offer.
- 那你会来吗  - 好啊
- So you'll come? - Yeah.
让我把地址告诉你
Let me give you the address.
好的 等一下
Okay. Hold on.
枫树街 32 号
It's 32 Maple Street.
再见
So see you later.
- 再见  - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
♪你嘴唇的触摸
♪ The touch of your lips ♪
♪紧挨着我的
♪ Next to mine ♪
♪让我兴奋
♪ Gets me excited ♪
♪- 让我感觉很好 - 哦 哦
- ♪ Makes me feel fine ♪ - ♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪你手的触摸
- ♪ The touch of your hand ♪ - ♪ Oh, oh... ♪
♪你甜蜜的问候
♪ Your sweet hello ♪
♪- 你内心的火焰 - 哦...
- ♪ The fire inside you ♪ - ♪ Oh... ♪
♪当你抱紧我
♪ When you're holding me close ♪
♪你的爱如此温暖
♪ Your love so warm ♪
♪温柔...
♪ And tender... ♪
♪曾经的我
♪ Once I had ♪
♪暗恋
♪ A secret love ♪
♪永存在
♪ That lived ♪
♪我的心中
♪ Within the heart of me ♪
♪太快了
♪ All too soon ♪
♪我的秘密爱情
♪ My secret love ♪
♪成为...
♪ Became... ♪
哦！
Oh!
你来了
Y-You're here.
这是一个圣诞奇迹
It's a Christmas miracle.
抱歉 我花了这么长时间
Sorry it took me so long.
我觉得那只猫中邪了
I think that cat's possessed.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
哦你不是桃子吗
Oh. Aren't you a peach?
进来吧
Come in! Come in.
艾琳
Eileen, um,
我很抱歉这里一团糟
I'm sorry the place is such a mess.
我没有...我是说 我试着清理了一下
I-I haven't... I mean, I tried to clean it up a bit,
但我实在想不通
but it's just beyond me.
我希望这不会让你感到不舒服
I hope it doesn't make you uncomfortable.
让我们打开这瓶酒
Let's open this wine.
呃 坐下 坐下 坐下
Uh, sit down. Sit down. Sit down.
♪你是多么美好...
♪ Just how wonderful you are... ♪
我希望你不用开很远 远吗
I hope you didn't have to drive far. Was it far?
没有我开车到处跑
Uh, no. I drive all over the place.
我帮你拿外套
Let me take your coat.
- 谢谢  - 哦 天哪
- Thanks. - Oh, my.
它又漂亮又柔软
It's so nice and soft.
这是我妈妈的
It's my mother's.
她一定是个非常优雅的女士
Well, uh, she must have been a real classy lady
有一个如此优雅的女儿
to have such a classy daughter.
事实上 她是个衣架子
She was something of a clotheshorse, actually.
希望是你喜欢的那种
I hope it's a kind you like.
哦 一定很好吃
Oh. I'm sure it's delicious.
其实 喝酒听起来不错
Drink sounds nice, actually.
让我们看看开瓶器藏在哪里
Let's see where the corkscrew's hiding.
呃 你知道
Uh, you know, -
我最近太忙了
I have just been so busy lately
我似乎记不起在哪里...
that I can't seem to remember where the...
但它一定就在这些乱七八糟的东西下面 对吗
But it's got to be here under all this mess, right?
你知道吗
You know what?
一位心灵手巧的年轻博士生曾经教过我一招
A very handy young PhD student once taught me a trick
如果您遇到困难 如何打开瓶子？
for how to open a bottle if you're ever stranded
没有开瓶器
without a corkscrew.
哲学家总是最大的酒鬼
Philosophers are always the biggest drunks.
虽然他有点可爱
Although he was kind of cute.
尤金·亨德森 哈佛大学
Eugene Henderson, Harvard.
我不知道你还能这么做
I had no idea you could do that.
这一招真不错
That was a great trick.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
现在我们需要一些眼镜
Now we need some glasses.
啊
Ah.
艾琳 我的圣诞救星
So to Eileen, my Christmas savior.
救世主？
Savior?
我什么都没做
I didn't do anything.
好吧 你是个朋友
Well, you're being a friend.
这就是一切 干杯
That's everything. Cheers.
♪我以为会持续一生的爱...
♪ A love I thought would last for a lifetime... ♪
天哪 太可怕了
God, that's awful.
不 那是...
No. That's a...
一拳的味道
punch of flavor.
这就是西拉葡萄酒
That's what a Syrah is.
希望你没花太多钱
Hope you haven't spent too much on it.
要...
To...
敬耶稣基督
To Jesus Christ.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
嗯
Mmm.
你一个人住在这里吗
Do you live here alone?
不
No.
哦 当然
Oh, uh, sure.
我...不 我不能有室友
I, uh... No, I can't have roommates.
我喜欢自己的空间
I, um, I like my own space.
我还是喜欢找乐子
I still like to have fun,
而且 我还能发出很大的声音
and, uh, I can make a lot of noise.
而且 你也看到了 我会把事情搞得一团糟
And, uh, I can make a mess, as you can see,
但是 我想放多大声就放多大声
but, uh, I can play music as loud as I want to.
我可以...
I can...
我可以尽情尖叫
I can scream as loud as I want to.
我也受不了室友
I can't stand roommates, either.
在大学里 我不得不把门锁上...
In college, I had to lock my door...
对了你上过大学
Oh, that's right. You were in college.
你学了什么？
What'd you study?
只是必修课程
Just the required courses.
嗯 如果我没有离开
Um, if I hadn't left,
无论如何 我可能都会成为一名秘书
I probably would have ended up a secretary anyway.
艾琳 你不是一个真正的秘书
Eileen, you're not really a secretary.
默里太太和史蒂文斯太太 她们是秘书
Mrs. Murray and Mrs. Stevens, they're secretaries,
因为他们听命行事
'cause they do what they're told,
这就是他们悲惨、下流的原因
and that's why they're miserable and nasty.
但是你 你的人生一定会很精彩
But you, you got a big life ahead of you, I'm sure.
好吧 我不是真正的秘书
Okay. I'm not a real secretary.
不 你没有
No, you're not.
- 因为你很聪明  - 嗯
- 'Cause you're smart. - Mm.
你很好奇 是吗
And you're curious, aren't you?
我的学习成绩一直不太好
Mm, I never really did very good in school,
所以我觉得我只是个普通人
so I'm just kind of average, I think.
别这么说 艾琳
Oh, don't say that, Eileen.
千万别这么说你...？
Never say that. Do you...?
你真以为自己是个正常人？
You really think you're a normal person?
如何正常？
Normal how?
我真是个不称职的女主人
I really am a bad hostess.
也许我们...
Maybe we'll, uh...
吃点东西会好受些
We'll feel better if we eat something.
我感觉很好
I feel fine.
我能用一下你的卫生间吗
Can I use your bathroom?
当然
Sure.
就在楼上
Just up the stairs.
♪在我们分享的时刻
♪ In the moments we shared ♪
♪你曾经说过你在乎...
♪ You once said you cared... ♪
是另一扇门 在右边
It's the other door, on the right.
♪我迷路了
♪ I'm lost ♪
♪为了纪念你...
♪ In the memory of you... ♪
♪我常听到的
♪ That so often I heard ♪
♪迷失
♪ Are lost ♪
♪在记忆中...
♪ In the memory... ♪
♪迷失
♪ Are lost ♪
♪在记忆中
♪ In the memory ♪
♪你的
♪ Of you ♪
♪我们的计划...
♪ Our plans... ♪
♪如此真诚
♪ Were all so sincere ♪
对不起
Sorry.
你有什么好遗憾的？
What do you have to be sorry for?
继续 吃吧吃吧吃吧吃吧
Go on. Go on. Eat. Eat. Yeah.
也吃点泡菜吧
Have a pickle, too.
为什么我们需要一把奶酪刀？
Why do we need a little, uh, cheese knife?
让我们的手保持干净？
To keep our hands clean?
不 这太荒谬了
No. It's all ridiculous.
一切都是
Everything is.
所有这些愚蠢的传统
All these stupid traditions,
就像圣诞节的典狱长和他的监狱
like the-the warden and his prison at Christmas.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我试着解释事情需要如何改变
I've tried explaining how things need to change,
但他只关心
but all he cares about
是男孩们是否会想起我
is whether or not the boys are gonna think about me
他们晚上在牢房里调戏自己
while they molest themselves in their cells at night.
上帝保佑
God forbid.
有严格的
There's a strict
摩尔黑德禁止手淫的政策
no masturbation policy at Moorehead.
在监狱里脱罪是违法的
It's illegal to get off in prison.
你知道的 对吧？
You know that, right?
好像这就是文明的堕落
As if that's the downfall of civilization,
人们达到高潮
people having orgasms.
你不能指望男人来解决任何问题
You can't count on men to fix anything.
人们为自己的欲望感到羞耻
People are so ashamed of their desires,
尤其是男人
especially men.
艾琳...
Eileen...
你现在可能已经知道了
as you can probably tell by now,
我的生活方式与大多数人有些不同
I live a little differently than most people.
不 你的房子很好
No, your house i-is nice.
- 不 很舒适
- No. - It's cozy.
我不是说房子我是说...
I don't mean the house. I mean...
我有自己的想法
I have my own ideas.
也许你我都有这样的想法
Maybe you and I share some of those ideas.
我们分享什么样的想法？
What kind of ideas do we share?
我能向你倾诉吗
May I confide in you?
当然
Of course.
是关于李·波尔克的
It's about Lee Polk.
- 是这样吗  - 是的
- It is? - Yes.
告诉我 亲爱的...
Tell me, honey...
是什么让一个人想要杀死自己的父亲？
what would make a person want to kill their father?
每个人都想杀死自己的父亲
Everybody wants to kill their father.
不 他们没有 谁告诉你的？
No, they don't. Who told you that?
真的 好好想想吧 艾琳
Really, think about it, Eileen.
因为李偷偷溜进了父母的卧室
Because Lee snuck into his parents' bedroom
在半夜...
in the middle of the night...
砍断了他父亲的喉咙
hacked through his father's throat
用一把旧菜刀
with an old kitchen knife,
并多次刺中他的胸部
and stabbed him in the chest repeatedly.
他的母亲声称 她以为有人闯入
His mother claimed she thought there'd been a break-in.
你是怎么睡过去的？
How do you sleep through something like that?
我不知道
I don't know.
你不知道所以我才叫她来
You don't. That's why I called her in.
我是说 你当时在场
I mean, you were there.
这个可怜的孩子几乎不敢看她 所以...
The poor boy could barely look at her, so...
所以事后 我就直截了当地问他
so afterwards, I just asked him point-blank.
我说...
I said...
我说："你父亲对你做了什么？"
I said, "What'd your father do to you?"
"是什么让你想这样对待你父亲的尸体？"
"What made you want to do that to your father's body?"
他在短短几分钟内就全说了出来
And he spilled it all in a matter of minutes.
以前从没人问过他
Nobody had ever bothered to ask him before.
没有人想过要问
No one had thought to ask.
你不想知道吗
Wouldn't you want to know?
你难道不好奇吗
Wouldn't you be curious?
是的
Yes.
你想知道吗
Do you want to know?
是的
Yes.
艾琳 你不能告诉任何人你明白吗
Eileen, you can never tell anyone. Do you understand?
你明白...答应我
You understa... Promise me.
我保证
Promise.
♪爱情怎么了...
♪ What happened to the love... ♪
你需要知道的第一件事
The first thing you need to know,
这不是我家
this isn't my house.
这是波尔克家
This is the Polk house.
我把波克夫人绑在楼下了
I have Mrs. Polk tied up downstairs.
艾琳艾琳
Eileen. Eileen.
艾琳
Eileen.
艾琳 请稍候
Eileen, please wait.
艾琳 求你了
Eileen, please.
我以为我一个人就能搞定 艾琳
I thought I could do this alone, Eileen.
请别走艾琳
Please don't go. Eileen!
求你了 别走求你了
Please, don't go. Please.
我以为你邀请我来是因为你喜欢我
I thought you invited me over here 'cause you liked me.
哦 我知道
Oh, I do.
是的 对不起 求你了 艾琳
I do. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Please, Eileen.
求你了 艾琳给我点时间
Just pl-please, Eileen. Just give me a moment.
请听我解释
Please just let me explain.
我需要...
I need...
我需要一个朋友
I need a friend.
昨天下午我来到这里
I came here yesterday afternoon
去找波尔克夫人谈谈
to talk to Mrs. Polk.
我说我看得出她很难过
I said I could see that she was upset
在我们与李见面之后
after our meeting with Lee,
她有什么想讨论的吗
was there anything she wanted to discuss.
她说："没什么 "于是我...
She said, "Nothing," so I...
我逼问她
I pressed her.
我把李告诉我的话告诉了她
I told her what Lee had told me.
她朝我吐口水 说我是变态
She spat at me, called me the pervert,
然后称她的丈夫为圣人
then called her husband a saint,
我留下了名片 让她考虑一下
and I left my card, told her to think about it.
我知道她不会打电话来然后我就走了
I knew she wouldn't call. Then I left.
现在 我昨晚睡不着觉
Now, I couldn't sleep last night.
因为我...
'Cause I...
我一直在想李告诉我的话
I couldn't stop thinking about what Lee had told me,
他父亲的所作所为
what his father had done,
以及他的母亲是如何让这一切发生的
and how his mother had let it happen.
我甚至都不记得开车过来的路了 我太生气了
I don't even remember the drive over here, I was so angry.
突然 我从她身边挤了过去
Suddenly I was pushing past her,
说："你怎么能这样做？
saying, "How could you do it?
你怎么能与这种酷刑同流合污？"
How could you be complicit in such torture?"
她厉声喝道
And she snapped.
她攻击我看到了吗
She attacked me. See?
看到了吗
See?
于是我为自己辩护
So I defended myself.
我们打了一架 我...我不知道发生了什么
We fought, and I... I don't know what happened,
但不知怎的 我们从楼梯上摔到了地下室
but somehow we fell down the stairs to the basement.
我以为她会杀了我
I-I thought she was gonna kill me,
于是我用椅子砸她 把她绑起来
so I hit her with a chair and tied her up.
我试着跟她理性地谈谈
I tried to talk to her rationally,
解释说我是来帮助李的
to explain that I was here to help Lee,
如果她愿意 我也可以帮助她
that-that I could help her, too, if she'd let me,
但是...但是她只是不停地尖叫
but... but she just kept screaming
我绑架了她 她丈夫是警察
that-that I'd kidnapped her and her husband was a cop
而我却要去坐牢
and I was gonna go to jail.
于是我在厕所里找到了一些可待因
So I found some codeine in a bathroom,
并让她安静下来
and got her to be quiet.
然后我给你打了电话
Then I called you.
因为 如你所见 我现在手头有点紧
Because, as you can see, I'm in a bit of a pinch.
我能做些什么？
What can I do?
我需要波尔克夫人坦白
I need Mrs. Polk to confess,
我需要一个证人 两个对一个
and I need a witness, two against one.
你明白吗
You understand?
哦 我不能进监狱
Oh, I can't go to jail.
好的
Okay.
在这里等着
Wait here.
艾琳等等...
Eileen. Wait...
太不可思议了
It's incredible.
为什么会有这个？
Why do you have that?
你为什么把它带到这里来？
Why did you bring that around here?
我爸爸病了
My dad's sick.
拿起来 告诉我你要怎么拿
Pick it up, and show me how you're gonna hold it.
很好 艾琳
That's very good, Eileen.
好的
All right.
酷一点
Be cool.
告诉我们真相吧 波尔克夫人
Just tell us the truth, Mrs. Polk,
我们就放你走
and we'll let you go free.
家庭可以痊愈
Families can heal.
你并没有迷失方向 没有人是
You're not a lost cause. No one is.
这并不容易
It can't have been easy,
嫁给这样一个男人
being married to a man like that.
很明显 你的日子不好过
You're obviously having a hard time.
你为什么不告诉我们这房子里发生了什么？
Why don't you tell us what happened in this house,
你为什么要帮你丈夫做这些事？
why you helped your husband do what he did?
然后我们就扯平了
And then we'll be even,
我们都可以走出这里 和...
and we can all walk out of here, and...
我们就能想办法帮助李
and we can figure out how to help Lee.
他妈的给我松绑给我松绑
Fucking untie me! Untie me!
让我出去
Let me out of here!
你这个疯婆子 滚出我的房子！
You crazy bitch, get out of my house!
你有大麻烦了 你以为你会
You're in big trouble, you think you're gonna
- 能逃过这一劫  - 艾琳
- get away with this! - Eileen.
你会在监狱里蹲很长时间
You're going to jail for a long time.
她在这里干什么？
What the hell is she doing here?!
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
我真的觉得你需要告诉我们真相
I really think you need to tell us the truth.
你到底在说什么？
What the hell are you talking about?!
如果你不...
If you don't...
我们可以把你绑在这里
we could leave you down here tied up,
没人能找到你
no one to find you.
人体寿命不长
The human body can't live very long
没有食物和水
without food and water.
迟早有一天 你会需要大便
Sooner or later, you're gonna need to take a shit.
我想你只能自认倒霉了
I guess you're just gonna have to shit yourself.
还有小便
And piss.
感觉不会很好
It's not gonna feel very good.
我不怕你
I'm not scared of you.
我了解你
I know you.
我知道你爸爸是谁
I know who your dad is.
如果你认识我爸爸 你应该感到害怕
If you know my dad, then you oughta be scared.
是吗 害怕一个拈花惹草的酒鬼
Yeah? Scared of a womanizing, drunk piece of shit
谁都知道他是个疯子？
who everybody knows is batshit crazy?
你以为他自己没有问题吗
You think he didn't have problems of his own?
你以为他没有自己的秘密吗
You think he didn't have secrets of his own, huh?
你以为你妈妈不知道吗
You think your mom didn't know about 'em?
认为没有...
Think it didn't...
我要杀了你
I am going to fucking kill you
如果你现在不开始说话的话
if you don't start talking right now!
请！
Please!
求求你 别杀我
Please, don't kill me.
只要你开口 我就不会杀你
I won't have to kill you if you talk.
我做不到
I can't.
请不要
No, please.
她不会帮你的说吧
She's not gonna help you. Talk.
除非你忏悔 否则我帮不了你
I can't help you unless you confess.
好的
All right.
你赢了
You win.
结婚时
When you get married
你有孩子...
and you have children...
结婚时要宣誓
You take an oath when you get married
尊敬并服从你的丈夫
to honor and obey your husband.
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand that.
起初 我...
At first, I...
一开始 我以为米奇
At first, I just, I thought Mitch
只是在他睡觉的时候看看他
was just checking on him in his sleep,
你知道 就像所有父亲一样
you know, like any father would,
他只是想确定
like he, he just wanted to be sure
他的儿子安然无恙地躺在床上
his son was safe and sound in bed.
有时我...
Sometimes I'd...
感觉到他下了床
feel him getting out of bed,
有时他回来时 我就能感觉到他
and sometimes I'd just feel him when he'd come back.
他...
And he'd...
吻我或...
kiss me or...
抱着我...
hold me and...
你知道吗
You know?
我们并没有真正在一起
And we hadn't really been together
自从李出生以来
since Lee'd been born.
但后来我...
But then I...
我下面开始感染
I started getting these infections down there.
我想这是我的错
I figured it was my fault.
然后我在想 如果米奇
And then I wondered if Mitch
他带了些东西回家 你知道吗
had brought something home with him, you know?
然后有一次
Then one time...
我半夜起来
I got up in the middle of the night.
我不记得为什么了
I don't remember why.
一杯水？我不知道
Glass of water? I don't know.
我想 我想这也许是个梦
I thought-I thought maybe it was a dream.
我...
I...
我走了进去
I went-I went and looked in.
我并没有马上意识到这一点
It didn't dawn on me right away.
我发誓I...
You know, I-I swear to you. I...
我是说...
I mean...
你不指望你丈夫
You don't expect your husband's
你知道吗
gonna do something like that, you know?
我是说 反正没人会相信
I mean, nobody would believe it, anyway.
然后我... 然后...
And then I... and then...
然后我想...
And then I figured...
然后我想 如果李是干净的...
And then I figured, if Lee was clean...
如果他是清白的
If he was clean,
睡前灌肠和洗澡...
an enema and a bath before bed...
那么对我们大家都好
then it would be better for all of us.
的确如此
And it was.
我知道我在做什么 这不是...
I knew what I was doing, it wasn't...
这不太对
it wasn't quite right.
我知道我知道
I did know that. I did.
但你会告诉谁呢？你知道吗
But who do you tell? You know?
我能告诉谁呢？
Who could I tell?
我是说 你要尽力而为
I mean, you do the best you can.
你知道有了孩子之后会发生什么吗
You know what happens when you have children?
你丈夫看你的眼神从未变过
Your husband never looks at you the same.
但在他和李上床之后
But after he went to bed with Lee,
他会来找我
he'd come to me.
就像卸下了一个沉重的包袱
It was like a big burden had been lifted.
他 他很放松
He was, he was relaxed.
他抱着我的感觉真好
It felt good, how he'd hold me.
他那时爱我
He loved me then.
他会轻声地吻我
He would whisper and kiss me.
这就是以前的样子...
It was the way it had been before...
那时我们年轻、快乐、相爱
when we were young and happy and in love.
感觉很好
It felt good.
这有什么不对吗...
Is that so wrong...
想有这种感觉？
to want to feel like that?
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
你还年轻 还没有心碎过
You're young, you haven't had your heart broken.
我在流血我在流血
I'm bleeding! I'm bleeding!
救救我救救我
Help me! Help me!
求你了求...帮帮我
Please! Plea... Help me!
- 我在流血  - 嘘
- I'm bleeding! - Shh! Shh!
- 帮帮我你会后悔的  - 艾琳 救救我
- Help me! You'll be sorry! - Eileen, help me!
我会告诉所有人你做了什么！
I'll tell everyone what you've done!
- 艾琳  - 医生
- Eileen! - A doctor!
去看医生
Get a doctor!
- 救我出去  - 艾琳 帮帮我
- Get me out of here! - Eileen, help me!
帮帮我
Help me!
不要！
No! No!
不
No.
不要！
No! No!
- 好的 好的 - 好的
Okay. Okay.
你为什么向她开枪？
Why did you shoot her?
我很难过
I was upset.
我们现在该怎么办？
What do we do now?
我们带她去我家
We take her to my house.
我爸爸总是把枪拿出来
My dad's always whipping his gun out.
人人皆知
Everyone knows it.
我们可以伪装成他是在停电时射杀她的
We can make it look like he shot her in a blackout.
他只是个酒鬼 对吧？
He's just a drunk piece of shit, right?
无论如何他都会死 或者发疯
He's gonna die anyway or go crazy.
医生是这么说的
The doctor said so.
我们带她一起走吧
So let's take her together and leave.
然后我们就可以去纽约过年了...
Then we could go to New York for the New Year...
只有我们两个人
just the two of us.
我爱你
I love you.
没关系
It's okay.
来吧
Come on.
好的
All right.
你先去你父亲家
You go ahead to your father's house.
在那儿等我
Wait for me there.
- 我去里面打扫一下
- Yeah. - I'll clean up inside.
我们不能留下任何证据
We can't leave any evidence behind.
- 我会等你的  - 我会很快的
- I'll be waiting. - I'll be quick.
艾琳
Eileen.
继续睡吧 爸爸
Go back to sleep, Dad.
你要去哪儿？
Where you going?
我可能要上路了
I might just get on the road.
那好吧
All right, then.
晚安
Good night.